<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.ransome1.sleek</id>

  <name>sleek</name>
  <summary>sleek is a todo app based on todo.txt, free and open-source</summary>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <developer_name>Robin Ahle</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <releases>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2021-01-13"/>
  </releases>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/ransome1/sleek</url>

  <recommends>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
    <control>gamepad</control>
  </recommends>

  <description>
    <p>sleek offers a clean and simple interface that can be used with mouse and keyboard, keyboard only or touch devices. You will use an easy to understand but powerful syntax to create todos. According to the concept of todo.txt you can add contexts to your todos or assign them to projects you're working on. Priorities can be set and if you add due dates sleek will send you notifications just in time.</p>
    <p>All that can be done typing plain text or guided by sleeks interface that for instance will show suggestions on contexts and projects while typing, offers pickers to ease the selection of due dates or set recurrence intervals, if your todos should repeat themselves.</p>
    <p>There is no cloud integration, but as sleek writes your todos into a plain text file, you can put it anywhere and sync it to all your devices. That also means if you don't have sleek at hand or if you don't like it any more you can just edit the todo.txt file with any text editor or other todo.txt application.</p>
    <p>Features</p>
    <ul>
      <li>An existing todo.txt file can be used or a new one can be created</li>
      <li>Todos can be added, edited, marked as complete (and vice versa) or deleted</li>
      <li>Existing todos can be used as templates for new ones</li>
      <li>Todos can be bulk archived to a done.txt file</li>
      <li>Completed todos can be shown or hidden</li>
      <li>Todos are grouped by priority</li>
      <li>Todos are sorted by due date within their priorities</li>
      <li>Todos can be enriched by contexts, projects, start dates, due dates</li>
      <li>Todos can repeat themselves based on a given due date. You can use a recurrence picker add it to the text field using: "rec:d" (daily), "rec:w" (weekly), "rec:m" (monthly), "rec:y" (annually)</li>
      <li>Available contexts and projects will be suggested according to your input</li>
      <li>Todos can be filtered by contexts and projects</li>
      <li>Filters are sorted alphanummerically</li>
      <li>Todos can be looked up using full-text search</li>
      <li>A due date can be set using a datepicker</li>
      <li>Hyperlinks are detected automatically and can be clicked using the icon</li>
      <li>Basic notifications: Will fire if a todo's due date is set for tomorrow or today</li>
      <li>Todos that include either contexts or projects can be shown or hidden entirely</li>
      <li>Dark and light mode can be toggled</li>
      <li>A file watcher rereads the file if it has been changed</li>
      <li>Multiple todo.txt files can be added</li>
      <li>Multiple languages are automatically detected or set by hand to German, English, Italian, Spanish and French</li>
      <li>Tabindex available</li>
      <li>Basic keyboard shortcuts are available</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.ransome1.sleek.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/main_dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/main_filter_dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/add_todo_typeahead.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/add_todo.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ransome1/sleek/master/assets/screenshots/linux/edit_todo.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
